本字幕由 ShinY 深影字幕组 原创翻译制作
深影字幕组论坛地址 http://shinybbs.com
翻译： 小坏玩意儿 HTC 爽爷 老虎娘 Echo 兰丰
校对： 爽爷  后期： mask
朱姆沃尔特级驱逐舰
The Zumwalt-class destroyer.
实验中的美国海军驱逐舰
需要海军和生产厂家的通力合作
Demanding the best from the Navy
才能将梦想化为现实
and the companies constructing her.
你们四位是新一代美国国防公司的代表
You four represent the next wave of U.S. defense companies
是你们致力于改善士兵们的生存状况
who will improve the lives of our military personnel
保证他们的安全 强化他们的装备
by keeping them safer and better equipping them
他们才能更好地保家卫国
to defend us.
先生们 一语以概之...
Gentlemen, together...
我们代表着国家海军的未来
we are the future of the United States Navy.
秘书官波特女士
Madam Secretary Porter,
为什么我们的标志比马克的小
why is my logo smaller than Marc's?
贝灵哲海运今年为海军
Beringer Marine laid down a million tons
贡献了一百万吨原钢
of raw steel this year.
而联合分点只提供小螺丝钉而已
United Equinox made a tiny screw.
我们提供的小螺丝钉
we made a teeny, tiny screw
可以承受一千两百度的温度变化
that could withstand a 1,200 degree temperature swing.
而且总数多得吓死你
And we made a crap-ton of them.
又按错什么东西了吗 麦基?
Is this another dramatic touch, McGee?
不是的 秘书官女士
Not exactly, Madam Secretary.
网络防护装置检测到
Network security detected
某种未授权的电子信号
an unauthorized electronic transmission.
所有装置自动关闭
Everything shuts down automatically.
你是指外部的网络攻击吗?
Does that mean someone's trying to hack in from the outside?
不 这种模式只在发生内部攻击时启用
No. Lockdown only happens if the attack's internal.
攻击就发生在这间屋子里面
The threat's in this room.
海军罪案调查组 第十一季第九集
NCIS S11E09
"勇气的考验"
我最近重看了一遍 太空城
I just reread Moonraker.
整个礼拜天都花在这个上面
Spent the whole day reading on Sunday.
真是好久没有这样了
Don't remember the last time that happened.
你经常看书吗?
You read a lot?
昨天晚上我出去喝酒
You know, I went out for a drink last night,
认识了一个女孩
and I met a girl.
笑起来很甜 身材一级棒
Great smile, great body.
你猜她是做什么的?
Guess what she does for a living.
我在考虑要不要去做变性手术 诺玛
I'm thinking about getting a sex change, Norma.
你在跟我说话吗 迪诺左探员?
You say something, Agent DiNozzo?
我只是想说话活跃一下气氛
I'm just trying to make conversation.
和我说话吗?
With me?
没错
Yeah.
我刚刚没有在听
I wasn't listening.
再说一次
Start over.
真的吗?
Really?
我猜跟我约会的那个妞是网球运动员
So, I guess it turns out that I'm dating a tennis pro.
猜猜她怎么给我电话号码的?
Want to know how she gave me her number?
枕头上给我留了这个
Boop! Left it on her pillow.
你在听吗?
Hello.
挺好的
That's nice.
这就完了?
That's it?
你想让我说什么?
What do you want?
有点反应好嘛
Well, a little something.
嘲笑啊 鄙视啊 都可以啊
Just a jibe, a scoff, a little stink-eye, you know?
我... 需要看到你有点情绪什么的
I just... I need something.
评论两句 给我个"呸"什么的
The riff, the pattere "p, th."
你开始有鄙视的眼神了 很好
Oh, you got a stink-eye in there. I can see it.
听着 再来一个"呸"就行了
Listen, I just need the "pah."
探员麦基在哪里?
Where's Agent McGee?
不应该把重担都给蒂姆一个人挑
The burden shouldn't always fall on Tim.
他够辛苦的了
He's suffered enough.
探员吉布斯呢?
What about Agent Gibbs?
嘿 老大 我和一个网球运动员在约会
Hey, boss, dating a tennis pro.
挺好的
That's nice.
我们出发
Let's go.
看到了吧 就是这样?
See?
发现尸体了吗?
We got a body?
是内部破坏
It's a breach.
我们不开车
We're not driving.
去哪里?
Where we going?
楼上
Upstairs.
怎么回事 莱昂?
What's happening, Leon?
安全模式下
In secure mode,
多重威胁预警中心的探测器
MTAC sensors constantly
会定期扫描电子信号
scan for electronic signals.
只要有非机构内的任何东西
Anything other than our equipment
发射出无线频率信号 房间就锁死
emits a radio frequency, room goes on lockdown.
不找到发射来源 没有人能离开这里
Nobody's allowed to leave till we find the source.
你是说监视器 窃听器什么的
Like a surveillance device, a bug.
是的
Right.
- 这种情况经常发生吗? - 不经常
- Does this happen a lot? - No.
脑子坏了才带这种东西来安全室
Not the brightest idea to bring one into a secure room.
所以他们才搜查你两遍 马克
That's why they're gonna check you twice, Marc.
省省吧 沃德
Save it, Ward.
现在可不是斗嘴的时候
Not exactly the time.
清查完毕
All clear.
我扫描了每一处角落 老大
I've scanned every square inch, boss.
座椅 墙壁 电脑台...
Seats, walls, computer console...
没有发现非法设备
no sign of any illicit devices.
假警报? 软件错误?
False alarm? Software glitch?
都有可能
Possible.
这么说可以允许
Does that mean we're free to let
我们的重要合作伙伴离开了 主任?
our valued corporate partners go, Director?
可以解除锁定了 伙计们
You can take us off lockdown, fellas.
- 是的 长官 - 先生们 这边走
- Yes, sir. - Gentlemen, please.
又发生故障了吗?
Another malfunction?
你不是每个人都搜过了吗 迪诺左探员?
I thought you searched everyone, Agent DiNozzo.
我以为你不想让我对国家秘书官
I didn't think you wanted me to pat down
进行贴身搜查呢 长官
the United States Secretary of the Navy, sir.
现在需要你这样做
Well, I do now.
请把胳膊抬起来 女士
Uh, raise your arms, please, ma'am.
我也没有办法 家里有两张嘴要养活
Just remember, I have mouths to feed.
两条金鱼
Two goldfish.
我可是家里的顶梁柱
I'm their only source of income,
而且他们超级... 无敌可爱
and they're-they're awfully cute.
放心 迪诺左 我跟你一样好奇
Relax, DiNozzo. I'm as anxious about this as you are.
我要搜查你的口袋 女士
I'm gonna have to search your pockets, ma'am.
你身上有什么针一类的锋利物品吗?
Do you have any needles or sharp objects?
这是流程
I have to ask.
没有 继续
No. Proceed.
一支笔?
A pen?
真把我吓了一跳呢 先生们
You had me worried for a moment, gentlemen.
那是什么鬼东西?
What the hell's that?
初步判定
Well, first impression,
是带闪存盘的针孔麦克风
it's a flash drive connected to a pinhole microphone.
找到窃听器了
We got our bug.
居然是我带进来的
I'm the breach.
好吧 我来澄清一下
Okay, let's clear the air right now.
我不知道是何时何地拿到那支笔的
I have no idea when or where I got that pen.
可能是在医生办公室 银行 酒店
Could have been a doctor's office, bank, restaurant.
印象中上次用这支笔
The last time I remember using it
是在昨天早上给女儿签许可单的时候
was when I signed a permission slip for my daughter yesterday morning.
一定是那个时候我拿起来放到兜里了
And I must have put the pen in my pocket after that,
但是我真的不知道那是一个窃听器
but I had no idea it was recording me.
知道了
Okay.
你相信我吗?
You believe that?
是的
Yes.
为什么?
Why?
我尊敬你的人品
Respect.
还有部门的信誉
For you and the office.
并且 除非有反向证据
And until there's evidence to the contrary,
否则你也只是有嫌疑而已 秘书官女士
you'll get the benefit of the doubt, Madam Secretary.
谢谢你 吉布斯探员
Thank you, Agent Gibbs.
当务之急是在信息泄露之前
Job now is finding who's responsible
找到是谁做的
before anything leaks.
昨天三点
I had classified briefings
我在美国国防部的非常规地点参加了机密报告
at three D.O.D. off-site locations yesterday,
会上讨论了很多战略部署的内容
and we talked enough deployment strategy
一旦泄露会让我效力的海军
to cause serious security problems
面临严重的安全问题
for the sailors and Marines I work for.
这是我唯一担心的 吉布斯探员
Understand, they are my only concern in this, Agent Gibbs.
艾比拿到了那支间谍笔 老大
Abby's got the spy pen, boss.
根据电池总容量和剩余的电量
Based on the battery size and the length of the charge left,
我们推断窃听已经持续了三十个小时左右
we think it's been recording for about 30 hours or so.
可以追踪窃听者吗?
Can we track who's listening?
这个不是实时传送的
It's not a live feed.
窃听器会存储数据
The bug stores the data internally,
也就是说 无论是谁放的这个
which means whoever planted it
都得想办法把数据下载回去
has to download the info.
假设数据已经被下载了
Which we have to assume they've already done.
我会警告五角大楼
All right, I will alert the Pentagon
我昨天参加的会议可能已经泄密
that my meetings yesterday were compromised.
我们应该让国安局介入调查
And we should bring in the NSA.
我刚刚申请跟进信息
I just put in a request for info.
他们有耳目专盯贩卖国家情报的事情
They got ears open for the sale of U.S. intel.
先确保事情还没有遭到那份儿上
Let's make sure it doesn't get that far.
你想怎么做我心里有数 老大
You zig, I zag, boss.
我和国安局打电话那段时间
While I was on the horn with NSA,
我拿到一份潜在威胁分析报告
I pulled a threat analysis report.
刚刚那十分钟他们就总结出报告了吗?
They put this together in the last ten minutes?
不 这是两年之前的报告
No. The paper's two years old.
但是文中确切地预示了这次外泄事件
But it predicts our breach exactly.
"隐秘录音设备
"Clandestine recording device,
高层职员
high-level government official,
日常用品
an everyday item
比如签字笔"
such as an ink pen."
巧合吗?
Coincidence?
我们得找撰写这份报告的人谈谈
We need to talk to the person who wrote this paper.
我还以为这里也要来次"清查"
I thought we were gonna get a cavity search coming in here.
真会说笑
Interesting.
嗯
Hmm
瞧啊 好家伙啊
Whoa, look at that.
最好别和麦基提这些 星际迷航 游戏座椅
We better not tell McGee about the Star Trek video game chairs.
说出来肯定让他羡慕嫉妒恨
It'll just irritate him.
这里像一个苹果商店一样
It's like an Apple Store.
两位来自海军罪案调查处吧
You must be NCIS.
欢迎来到国安局网路运营中心
Welcome to the National Security Operations Center.
我是国安局特别探员乍得・弗莱德林
I'm NSA Special Agent Chad Flynderling.
叫我弗莱林就可以
You can call me Flynn.
弗莱林
Flynn.
好比 电子世界争霸战
Like Jeff Bridges
里的杰夫・布里奇斯?
in Tron?
那是原创
That's original.
抱歉 请见谅
Sorry. I'm sorry.
目前我对国安局的公众认知尤为敏感
I'm sensitive to NSA's public perception right now.
可别把我这当成数据狂人扎墩儿的避世宝地
We're not just a bunch of reclusive data nerds.
这里经手的工作五花八门 员工也是形形色色
Our employees are as diverse as the work that we do here.
我发誓 我再听到
And I swear, if I have to hear another crack
关于 星际迷航 座椅的玩笑...
about the Star Trek chairs...
嘿 可瞧仔细了
Oh, hey, look at those.
都没有注意到他们
Didn't even notice them.
我浏览过你问到的威胁报告
I reviewed the threat report you called about.
- 你写的吗? - 不是
- You write it? - Well, no.
你有什么需要 我可以协助你调查
Uh, but I can assist you with anything you might need.
我们要找的是原作者
We asked for the original author.
第一准则 按要求办事
Make it so, Number One.
有什么为难的?
What's the problem?
嗯
Hmm
要说那些不食人间烟火的数据狂人...
About those reclusive data freaks I was talking about...
这得等多久?
So how long does this go on?
等等就好
Yeah, just wait for it.
吉布斯 迪诺左探员
Uh, Agents Gibbs and DiNozzo,
向你们介绍国安局的数据分析员
I give you NSA Analyst
艾丽・毕晓普
Ellie Bishop.
她宁愿选在这里
She prefers to do her
完成手头无需避讳的工作
unclassified research in here.
我想我们早就谈妥首要准则了 弗莱林
I thought we discussed rule number one, Flynn.
只要我戴着耳机 就不闻"窗外事"
When my earbuds are in, flash the desk light.
这次由不得我做主
Couldn't help it.
我是毕晓普
Bishop.
幸会
It's good to meet you.
抱歉 我正忙... 赶工
Sorry, I was in the middle of... stuff.
没错 我写的 怎么了?
Yup. That's my work. What's up?
你看都没看就知道啊
You didn't even look at it.
我来国安局的第三天写的
I wrote it my third day at the NSA.
一个周三早晨
It was a Wednesday morning.
我刚吃完一盒可可麦脆片
I just finished a box of Cocoa Pebbles.
我清楚记得是因为
I remember that because it was
盒子里面的奖品 激发了我的写作灵感
the prize inside the box that inspired the entire paper.
我来猜猜 奖品是一支笔?
Let me guess. A pen?
显而易见的日常用品
An everyday object hiding in plain sight.
灵感一触即发
It clicked.
你那洋洋洒洒二十五页之多的国家安全策略
So you got 25 pages of national security strategy
就来源于早餐麦片?
from inside a breakfast cereal?
为了更好地防御各种袭击
In order to better prepare for attacks,
我虚构了一些尚未发生过的威胁
I dream up threats that haven't happened yet.
你倒是一梦成谶
This dream came true.
被我言中了啊
So I was right.
海军部长被窃听
Secretary of the Navy was bugged.
安全情报人员岌岌可危
Security intel is at risk.
真是够呛
Which is bad.
但是我把报告交给我的上司
But I submit my reports to my superiors,
随后又发放给相应人员
who then distribute them accordingly.
但是凡有基本安全许可的人都能接触到
Anyone with basic security clearance could have access.
这份报告你有给过其他人吗?
Did you give this paper to anybody else?
没有
No.
你是想问我有参与此事吗?
Are you asking if I'm in on it or something?
没... 没有的事情...
Uh, no, I... I'm not, I...
我只动笔写了脚本
I wrote the playbook, but I have
但是我真不知道谁负责操作
no idea who's running it.
抱歉
Sorry.
希望你能找到嫌犯
Hope you find your guy.
总之是幸会
It was nice to meet you.
我刚刚就说过
Like I said,
她不做外勤
she's not a field agent.
我可不聋 杰夫・丹尼尔斯
I can still hear you, Jeff Daniels.
电子世界争霸战 里面就没有这么个人
Jeff Daniels wasn't in Tron.
那个人叫杰夫・布里奇斯
That was Jeff Bridges.
弗莱林 你竟然是电影忠粉呢
Flynn, you are a fan.
喂 达克?
Yeah, Duck?
是的 这就回去
Yep, we're on our way back.
又发现一支窃听笔
We have got a second pen.
所以我想...
So I guess this means
- 我跟你们走一趟 - 不行
- I'm riding with you guys. - No.
你不行 她去
No, but she is.
什么? 为什么?
What? Why?
正如你承认的
'Cause, like you said,
脚本是你写的 对吧?
you wrote the playbook, right?
在这呆着做什么?
What are we doing here?
等达克过来 这里的法医
I'm waiting for Ducky, our M.E.
通俗点说就是"验尸员"
That stands for "medical examiner."
我又不是没见过这场面
This isn't my first case.
我想知道的是要我来做什么?
I meant, what am I doing here?
我分析巨幅数据
I analyze big-picture data,
为全球反恐战争制定详细策略
present detailed strategies in the global war on terror.
每一步棋都得花上几年时间来部署
Chess moves that can take years to implement.
你喜欢下棋?
You enjoy playing board games?
听着 我能提供的所有信息都在那份报告里面
Look, everything I can offer you is in that report.
我人在这里有什么用吗?
What good can I do in person?
说不好 但是你可以
I don't know, but you can start
先补看下卷宗
by catching up on the case file.
是的
Yes.
那你能给一个时限吗?
Well, then, can you tell me how long?
当然我可以等
Of course I can hold on.
估计你不是联调局的人 你来就是想
I don't suppose you're from the FBI and you've come to tell me
告诉我一切都是误会?
that all this is a misunderstanding?
抱歉 我是国安局的 我叫...
Sorry, NSA. My name...
这就不沾一点边
That is totally irrelevant.
我十分钟前刚刚和那个人联系过
I was just talking to the man ten minutes ago.
华府的法医故意不接我电话
The D.C. M.E. is dodging my calls.
达克 我还以为你说的是窃听器
Duck, I thought this was about another bug,
- 没有想到有尸体 - 都有
- not a body. - It's both.
多亏全境通告 那个法医又发现一支窃听笔
Thanks to our BOLO, the M.E. found a second pen
在他再次排查这个人的个人物品时发现的
when he went back through this man's personal effects.
他叫做克洛德・谢尔曼
He's Claude Sherman,
联合分点电子的会计师
accountant for United Equinox Electronics.
是的 他今早去过
Yeah, he worked
多方反恐警报中心一下设公司工作
for one of the companies in MTAC this morning.
谋杀吗?
Murder?
不是 自然死亡
No, natural causes.
两天前突发心肌梗塞
Myocardial infarction two days ago.
达克 那么尸体怎么到我们这里来了?
Ducky, then what's he doing here?
尸体与个人物品结伴而行
Body and personal effects travel together
以免断了证据链
in order to preserve the chain of evidence.
我早就说过 我是老手
Like I said, this is not my first case.
停下
Stop.
- 达克 那支笔呢? - 找不到了
- Ducky, where's the pen? - It's missing.
所以我这一整早儿都在打电话
That's why I've been on the phone all morning.
是的 经由
Yeah, according
验尸办公室确认
to the M.E.'s office,
一名联邦调查局探员
an FBI agent
在九点十五分的转移工作之前
collected the personal effects
整理收集了他的个人财物
just before the transfer at 0915.
问题是当我打电话确认时
The problem is, when I called to confirm,
联邦调查局却声称对此毫不知情
the FBI doesn't know anything about it.
- 有人伪装成了探员 - 看来是这样的
- Somebody posing as an agent. - It would appear so.
给我们留下一具尸体以及更多的问题
Leaving us a body and more questions.
是谁偷了这支笔?
Who stole the pen?
是把它安插在海军秘书官的身上的
Was it the same person who planted it
那个人吗?
on SECNAV?
这之间有什么联系?
What's the connection?
抱歉... 你怎么称呼?
I'm sorry... what was your name again?
毕晓普
Bishop.
你有头绪了?
You got something?
是的 呃 算是吧
Yeah, uh, maybe.
你们这边有吃的吗?
You got any food around here?
随便什么都行
Anything?
我们会找到的 快来
We'll find stuff. Come on.
五角大楼拒绝提供关于海军秘书官的
Pentagon refuses to release any of the minutes
任何会议记录
from SECNAV's briefings.
一旦情报泄露 全世界都会知道的
Once the intel leaks, the whole world will know.
是的 我也是这么告诉他们的
Yeah, it's what I told them,
但是他们只关心些关于俄罗斯
except all they could say was,
中国 叙利亚 伊朗
topics of discussion
之类的议题
included Russia, China, Syria and Iran.
那倒是缩小了范围
That narrows it down.
是的
Yeah.
那就是她?
That her?
她都下到这里来了?
She fall down?
哦 呃 别在意我这边这么乱
Oh, uh, don't let the chaos fool you.
我就是这么工作的
This is just how I work.
好吧 科学怪人
All right, Jeff Goldblum,
有人在海军秘书官身上安插了窃听器
guy plants a bug on SECNAV,
并获取了窃听的内容
uploads the data.
他要这些信息做什么?
What's he do with it?
说吧
Go.
你们读过我的论文了吗?
Did you read my paper?
读了... 一部分 但是我...
Some... some of it, but I...
时间很紧 我...
Time is a factor here, and I...
那是婚戒吗? 你结婚了吗?
Is that a wedding ring? Are you married?
今晚我就把报告发给你们 好吗?
I'll have my report to you by tonight, okay?
- 报告? - 嗯哼
- Report? - Mm-hmm.
今天晚上?
Tonight?
等等 回到刚刚那个话题
Wait, let's back the truck up.
你几岁?
How old are you?
不是说时间很紧吗
I thought time was a factor around here.
谈论我的个人隐私不是很浪费时间吗?
Isn't talking about my personal life a waste of it?
- 不是 - 是的
- No. - Yes.
依我所见 这个人
Well, the way I see it, our guy
有三个选择 其一 他会以信息披露的名义
has three options. One: he releases
把信息公布出去
the information in the name of full disclosure.
但是要是如此 他早就这么做了
Which he would have already done.
其二 他会把信息卖给我们的敌对势力
Two: he sells the data to the enemy.
但是他不可能事先获悉
Except he had no way of knowing
自己能窃听到什么样的情报
what kind of intel the bug would record.
所以需要寻找合适的买家
Needs to find the right buyer.
这就需要时间
Which takes time.
所以就只剩第三个选项了
Leaving us with option three:
他直接把信息卖还给我们
he sells the information back to us.
敲诈勒索
Extortion.
是的 呃 等等 那... 那只是我的猜测
Yeah, uh, wait, tha-that... that was just a guess.
我们得去警告海军秘书官办公室
We need to alert the SECNAV's office
这个人可能会打电话过去
this guy might be calling.
- 他联系过了 - 敲诈?
- He just did. - Extortion?
倒计时已经开始了
Clock's already started.
下午十二点三十分 海军秘书官办公室
12:30 p.m., SECNAV's office was contacted
收到一封加密的电子邮件
via an encrypted e-mail.
如果我们不在一个小时内向一个海外账户
We have one hour to deposit $10 million
汇款一千万美元的话 他就把情报泄露出去
into an offshore account or he leaks the intel.
我们能追踪到邮件来源吗?
Can we track the communication?
不能 发送这封邮件的人
No, who's ever behind this
懂得计算机的加密方法
knows their way
而且知道如何躲起来
around computer code and knows how to hide.
有没有可能
What are the chances
在汇款期限之前转到他?
of catching this guy before the deadline?
我们只要把钱汇过去就行了
Well, they get better if we just pay him.
- 他想要什么给他就是了 - 不行
- Give the man what he wants. - No.
我们不喜欢
We don't like
给恐怖分子任何东西
giving terrorists anything,
更别说是纳税人的钱了
much less taxpayer money.
我也是
Neither do I,
但是就像我对我国安局的上司说得那样
but like I told my boss at NSA,
这是工作需要
it's the cost of doing business.
如果我们把钱汇到了那个账户
If we deposit the money into the account
并且他试图取钱 那我们就有迹可循了
and he accesses it, it gives us something to trace.
这都在我的论文中提到了
It's all outlined in my paper.
是这个间谍
Would that be the same paper our spy
可以用来参考的那篇论文吗?
could be using as a paint-by-numbers?
他会知道这是我们的战术
He'll know that's our strategy.
他不管怎样都会猜到的
He would have guessed it anyway,
这就成为了国安局与他解密技术的对抗了
which makes it our NSA codes against his.
从统计学上来说 我们的胜算更大
And statistically, the odds are in our favor.
这是我们找到他的最好办法
It's our best way of finding him.
统计数据不会说谎
Statistics don't lie.
是的 但是我们要找的人会
Yeah, but our bad guy might.
会说谎?
Lie?
- 说什么慌? - 我们不知道
- About what? - We don't know
关于他的任何信息或是他想要什么
anything about him or what he wants.
他要钱 不是吗?
He wants money, right?
前提是他确实没有留一手的话
Unless he hasn't shown his full hand.
继续搜集情报直到有所进展
Keep digging till we find it.
这一点... 一点都说不通
That doesn't... doesn't make sense.
有事你需要凭着直觉走
Sometimes you got to go with your gut.
没错 但是无论如何 我们都应该同意
Sure, but gut logic aside, I think we can all agree here
切实的逻辑推理更好
that actual logic is better.
那我们就拭目以待吧
Well, we're about to find out.
海军秘书官刚刚批准了
SECNAV just approved
毕晓普的计划方案
Bishop's game plan.
给国安局提供汇钱的方案
Gave NSA the lead on the money-drop.
波特有话要对我们说 吉布斯
Porter wants to have a word with us, Gibbs.
好的
Good.
我在我的公司会计身上
The same kind of surveillance device
找到了相同的窃听设备
was found on my corporate accountant.
我没有在你的雇员身上
I didn't plant
安插什么的窃听器
a bug on your employee,
而且我非常肯定
and I sure as hell didn't plant a bug
没有在海军部长的身上安插窃听器
on the Secretary of the Navy!
你有种就起诉我叛国罪试试
You got stones accusing me of treason.
没必要这么争锋相对
There's no sense pointing fingers.
别装什么爱国主义者 沃德
Quit playing the patriot, Ward.
我就是爱国主义者
I am a patriot.
我们公司服务这一军事组织
My company's been serving this military
整整四代之久
for four generations.
我们可不是什么刚起家的战争投机者
We're not some startup war profiteer.
别说了
That's enough.
我理解你因为公司机密泄露
I understand you're concerned
而感到担忧
about corporate secrets being leaked.
就算没有泄露
Even if nothing leaks,
这种事也足够让我倾家荡产
word of this would kill me on Wall Street.
我们是在谈论数以亿记的资金
We're talking hundreds of millions.
我们已经着手调查
We are following up on the device
你雇员身上的窃听设备了
found on your employee,
马克 但是你得给我们时间
Marc, but give us time to do our jobs.
我向你们保证
I can assure you both
我们所有最好的探员都在
that our best agents are
全天候地处理这一案件
working on this around the clock.
我没有说错吧 吉布斯探员?
Isn't that right, Agent Gibbs?
我很肯定我们刚刚才停手 秘书官女士
Oh, I'm pretty sure you just took us off the clock, ma'am.
两位 失陪一下
Gentlemen, if you'll excuse me for a moment.
我已经被这事搞得焦头烂额了...
I'm getting hit on all sides with this...
五角大楼 白宫
Pentagon, White House.
谁都不想再见到任何其他情报丑闻
Last thing anybody needs is another intel scandal,
而国安局已经为这种威胁做好了准备
and NSA is prepared for this kind of threat.
我们也是 秘书官女士
So are we, Madam Secretary.
我需要你保持最好的工作状态 莱昂
And I want you to keep up the good work, Leon.
我不是要让你坐冷板凳
I'm not benching you;
但是我需要更多选手来参与这场比赛
I'm just adding more players to the game.
不同的选手有着不同的本事
Different players have different strengths.
没错 作为教练 我对阵容
Yes, and as head coach, I have the lineup
有着话语权 主任
just the way I want it, Director.
明白了吗?
Is that understood?
每个人都关注着我这样一个
Everybody's looking
没有军事背景的女海军秘书官
at a female SECNAV with no military background,
质疑这两点是否会制约我
wondering if either one of those things
成为一个合格海军秘书官
are gonna be a factor.
我希望通过妥善处理此事 来回击他们
I'd like to answer them by setting this right.
因此 我需要竭尽全力得到大家的支持
And to do that, I need all the help I can get.
尤其是你们的帮助
Especially yours.
哦 上帝
Oh, God.
该死的钢笔 告诉我答案
Stupid pen, give me answers.
你在那里站多久了?
How long have you been standing there?
哦 几分钟而已
Oh, just a few minutes.
- 我以为你知道 - 不
- I thought you knew. - No.
但是你一直跟我说话来着
But you were talking to me.
不 我... 我在自言自语
No, I... I was talking to myself
还有和一支... 钢笔说话
and a... pen.
但是现在我不会再说话了
But now I'm not talking anymore,
谁知道 谁在听我说话 不是吗?
'cause who knows who's listening?
你认为谁在听你说话呢?
Who do you think's listening?
NSA
哦 不... 不要道听途说
Oh, no... don't believe everything you hear.
我的意思是 我们不会随意
I mean, we don't randomly listen
监听谈话和电话
to conversations and phone calls.
胡说八道
我是认真的
I'm serious.
和你们一样 我们需要得到许可才可以这样做
We need a court order just like you.
我们当中确实有不法分子
We've had a few bad apples,
但是我们都是好人
but we're good people
维护法律秩序 做出改变
out to uphold the law and make a difference.
那么 你没有监听我的电话?
So you haven't bugged my phone?
听着 我可以证明我是过来帮忙的
Look, I can prove I'm here to help.
我根据华府法医的描述画了这个
I drew this using D.C. examiner's description
我们正在寻找的那个冒牌联邦调查局探员
of our bogus FBI agent, fed it
通过在国家安全局的数据库里面搜索
into the NSA database, and got a hit on a guy named
找到一位名为鲁道夫・斯大林的人
Rudolph Stalin.
鲁道夫・斯大林
是的
Okay.
他是美国公民
Rudolph Stalin is an American citizen
有国际间谍案底
with a history of international espionage
与俄国有深厚的政治牵连
and strong political ties to Russia.
小胡子不错
And a very nice mustache.
我不知道是否算作一种讽刺
I wonder if it's supposed to be ironic.
我们已经监听他整整一年时间
He's been on our radar for about a year.
啊哈 嗯 他是美国公民
Aha, hmm, and he is an American citizen.
这就是我们需要许可的原因
Which is exactly why we needed a court order.
我记得几个月之前在读他的档案的时候
I remember reading his file a few months ago
我正在喝奶油蘑菇汤
over a bowl of cream of mushroom soup.
我... 我通常使用食物来联想记忆
I... I food-associate.
哦
Oh.
我... 我只是...
I... I'm just...
我对你绘画的本事表示诧异
I'm still stuck on the fact that you can draw.
我的意思是 虽然没有凯特画得好
I mean, this isn't Kate good,
但是还是非常不错的
but it's good good.
谁是凯特?
Who's Kate?
这... 这需要花费几个小时
That... that would take a few hours
和整整一盒纸巾来讲述
and a whole box of tissues.
好的 那么 我们先发布通缉令吧
Okay, well, then we should get this BOLO out first,
然后我去调查一下国家安全局那边进展如何
and I wanted to check up on the NSA operation.
嗯哼
Mm-hmm.
嘿 吉布斯 你知道毕晓普会画画吗?
Hey, Gibbs, did you know that Bishop can draw?
是的 她还在这里
Yeah, she's still here.
为什么?
Why?
好的
Okay.
艾比?
Abby?
怎么了? 是关于汇款的事情吗?
What? Is it about the money-drop?
也许我们应该谈一谈凯特的事情
Maybe we should have that talk about Kate.
负责人听到枪响 报警
Manager heard the shots, called the police.
现场没有目击证人
Nobody saw the shooter.
国家安全局已经支付勒索费用
NSA deposited the extortion money,
我们的间谍通过咖啡店的无线网络接收了汇款
and our spy accessed it using the coffee shop's Wi-Fi.
不是我接收一千万美金的首选场所
It's not the first place I'd come to collect $10 million.
探员弗莱德林想到同样的事情
Agent Flynderling thought the same thing.
因此他在呼叫支援之前就事先进行跟踪
That's why he came to follow up before calling in a task force.
三处近距离射杀 正中胸部
Three gunshot wounds to the chest at close range.
根据火药残留痕迹和组织损伤程度
Based on the stippling and tissue damage,
他没有任何反击机会
he never had a chance.
甚至还没有来得及下车
Barely got out of his car.
- 伏击 - 老大
- Ambushed. - Boss,
他的口袋里面有东西
he's got something in his pocket.
嘿 老大 是不是她的...
Hey, boss, isn't this her...
我的报告
My report.
你说得对 吉布斯探员
You were right, Agent Gibbs.
不是这样的 毕晓普
It's not about that, Bishop.
有人在海军秘书官身上
Somebody plants a surveillance device
放置了监听设备
on the Secretary of the Navy,
并且敲诈了美国政府
and extorts the U.S. Government.
很可能和从华府验尸房里面偷窃
Likely the same guy who posed as an FBI agent
第二支窃听笔的冒牌探员是同一人
to steal a second spy pen from the D.C. morgue.
鲁道夫・斯大林...
Rudolph Stalin...
他因贩卖美国情报给俄国
he's an American wanted
而被通缉
for selling U.S. intel to Russia.
我被他的名字和小胡子
With a name and a mustache
深深震撼
like that, I... I'm shocked.
但是当国家安全局试图付款
But when the NSA tried
并追踪汇款之时...
to pay him off and track the deposit...
他杀害了国家安全局的弗莱德林探员
He murdered NSA Agent Flynderling
并携款潜逃
and got away with the money.
事实上 我检查了海外账号
Actually, I just checked the offshore account.
那笔钱依旧在里面
The extortion money's still there.
他弃一千万美金于不顾
He left behind ten million bucks.
- 根本说不通 - 可能枪杀之后吓坏了吧
- That doesn't make any sense. - Could've panicked after the shooting.
也许他没有我们所想那么专业
Maybe this guy's not as professional as we thought.
或者也许
Or maybe it's not about
一开始就和美国政府无关
Uncle Sam's money in the first place.
鲁道夫・斯大林可以得到什么
What... what else does Stalin get
通过引诱并杀害一个联邦探员?
by luring and killing a federal agent?
证明 向另外一位买家证明
Authentication. Proof to another buyer
他的情报属实
that his intel is genuine.
有人愿意支付超过一千万美金
Somebody willing to pay more than ten mil.
他在利用我们?
So he used us?
这个家伙在下很大的一盘棋
This guy was playing chess,
我从来没有意识到
and I never even saw it.
我知道我应该怎么做了
I know what I have to do.
清零
Reset.
重新开始
I'll start over.
- 毕晓普 - 我可以的 这次
- Bishop. - I'll get it this time.
我只是需要时间清理思路而已
I just need some time to clear the chessboard.
毕晓普
Bishop.
休息一下
Take a break.
买杯苏打
Go get a soda.
没有时间 没有现金
There's no time, and I have no cash.
拿着
Take it.
怎么了 艾比?
Yeah, Abbs?
- 你能到实验室一趟吗? - 好的
- Can you come to my lab? - Yep.
米开朗基罗 莎士比亚 达芬奇 海明威
Michelangelo, Shakespeare, da Vinci, Hemingway.
今天你可以把我列入他们的队伍了 吉布斯
Today, you can count me amongst their ranks, Gibbs.
我每天都这样做的 艾比
I do every day, Abbs.
你得到什么信息了?
What do you got?
大师级的线索
A masterpiece.
看起来好像是日期和时间而已
Well, it looks like a date and time stamp.
有时 伟大的艺术作品往往最简单
Sometimes the greatest works of art are simple.
- 你搞定那支笔了吗? - 不 我没有
- You got into the pen? - No. I failed.
内存芯片加密极好
The internal memory chip was too well encrypted.
那么这是什么 艾比?
Then what is this, Abbs?
这是通过无线传感器登陆芯片
That is the last day and time
的最后日期和时间点
the chip was accessed by the Wi-Fi transmitter.
啊 这是发送端?
Ah. That the send-y part?
是的
Yes.
所以 我不能告诉你
So, I can't tell you
我们苦苦寻找的坏家伙究竟从里面下载了什么
what our bad guy downloaded from the pen,
但是 通过发送端
but, because of the send-y part,
我可以告诉你 他何时做的
I can tell you when he did it.
是的 昨天
Yeah. Yesterday.
下午七点二十三分
7:23 p.m.
假设海军秘书官依旧把这支笔放在
And assuming that SECNAV still had the pen
她的口袋里面... 我查看了她的时间表
in her pocket... I cross-referenced her schedule.
波特当时正在和她的女儿在饭店用餐
Porter was at a restaurant having dinner
鲁道夫・斯大林就是在此时下载的
with her teenage daughter when Stalin was downloading.
他需要离她多近的距离?
How close would he have to be?
非常 这是一支很小的钢笔... 天线很短
Close. It's a small pen... small antenna.
所以我检查了饭店附近街道的监控录像
So I pulled street surveillance footage from
发现斯大林正坐在他的车里
near the restaurant, and found Stalin sitting in his car,
进行贩卖情报的勾当
committing high treason.
我猜测 耳目无处不在确实很有帮助
I guess having eyes and ears everywhere can be helpful.
但是不要告诉毕晓普 我这样说
But don't tell Bishop I said that.
车牌号码
License plate.
已列为全国通缉 吉布斯
Already added to the BOLO, Gibbs.
我们找到这家伙的机会
Our chances of finding this guy
大大增加
just skyrocketed.
艾比 干得真好
Abbs, that's really great work.
请节哀顺变
I'm sorry for your loss.
那个被杀的探员... 是你的朋友吗?
The agent who was killed... was he a friend of yours?
更像是一个兄长
More like an older brother.
怎么了?
Everything okay?
不能和家人
It's tough not being able
谈论我的工作很难
to talk to my family about what I do.
你应该看看我告诉我的妈妈
You should've seen my mom when I told her
接受俄克拉荷马州以外的工作时 她的表情
I was taking a job outside of Oklahoma.
你为什么这么说?
Why did you?
这就是父亲
Mm. That's the difference
和母亲的不同
between Mom and Dad.
他的首要原则是安逸使人灭亡
His first rule is: comfort makes for complicity.
意为唯有挑战自我才能成长
Means the only way to grow is by challenging yourself.
这有助于让我们记住为什么选择这份工作
Well, it helps to remember why we do the job.
继续向前
Keeps us going.
我该回国家安全局了
Actually, I should get back to NSA.
想走没有那么容易
Mm. You're not getting off that easy.
吉布斯也喜欢规矩 第四十五条
Gibbs likes rules, too. Number 45:
清理干净你的烂摊子
always clean up your mess.
- 怎么办? - 对初学者来说
- How? - Well, for starters,
全国通缉令锁定了鲁道夫・斯大林
the BOLO came back on Rudolph Stalin.
我们知道他在哪里了
We know where he is.
来吧 时间不等人
Come on. Time's a-wastin'.
好的 谢谢
Okay, thanks.
交警说斯大林的车
Metro PD says Stalin's car
还停在前面的一个停车场
is still parked in a lot out front.
他们不确定他在哪个电影院
They're not sure which theater he's in,
但是只有两家 你想让我去哪里?
but there are only two screens. Where do you want me?
我射击和实地训练得了满分
I aced my weapons and field training.
你有枪吗 爱多・安妮?
You got a gun, Ado Annie?
音乐剧《俄克拉荷马》中的人物
我把它落在我的流苏小马车上了
I left it in my surrey with the fringe on top.
别对我引用 俄克拉荷马
Don't quote Oklahoma to me.
待在车里
Stay in the car.
好吧
You bet.
他
Him.
是他!
That's him!
联邦探员!
Federal agent!
停下 停下 停下!
Stop, stop, stop!
毕晓普 你为什么用车撞他?
Bishop, why'd you hit him with the car?
... 其实是他撞上的车
Well... technically, he ran into the car.
必须说 这是我的直觉 不错吧?
Got to say, that was a gut move. Gut's good, right?
我们故意逼他出来的
We intentionally flushed the guy out.
吉布斯一直把守着出口
Gibbs had the exit covered the whole time.
什么?
What?
她使了个绝招 老大
She pulled a Palmer on this guy, boss.
至少他不会反抗了
At least he'll go quietly.
律师来之前我什么都不会说
I'm not saying anything without a lawyer.
你们用车撞我
You hit me with a car.
我以为他要逃脱了
I thought he was getting away.
档案上说他高中时是跑步健将
I read in his file that he was a high school track star.
我几乎能过目不忘
I remember almost everything I read.
不止包括一些审讯笔录
Which includes more than a few interrogation transcripts.
什么意思?
Meaning what?
我有一个主意
I have an idea.
等等 这些
Hang on. These.
你在做什么?
What?
我需要借用一下
I need to borrow this.
谢谢
Thank you.
审讯的主要原则
Now, a major principle of an interrogation
是让嫌疑人自己得出结论 是吧?
is to let the suspect draw their own conclusions, right?
就是说 只要我没有说我是他的律师
Which means, as long as I never say I'm his lawyer,
只要他没有问...
as long as he never asks...
站住
Stop.
我能行的
I can keep up.
你撞他之前他看见你了吗?
Did that guy see you before you hit him?
没有
Mm-mm.
听着 我们找了公共律师...
Look, we called the public defender...
你...
Hey. What...
终于来了 你是我...?
Finally. Are you my...?
抱歉没有换衣服
Sorry for the outfit.
今天我本该休息的 艾丽・毕晓普
Today was supposed to be my day off. Ellie Bishop.
你问他问题了吗?
Have you been asking him questions?
法律规定我们能
Legally, we can ask
想问多少问多少
as many questions as we want.
律师不在 嫌疑人是否回答取决于自己
Up to the suspect to talk without a lawyer.
没错 你想回答吗?
That's true. Do you want to talk?
我们不应该先私下谈谈吗? 或者...
Shouldn't we speak somewhere in private first? Or...
听你的 我已读过卷宗
It's up to you. I mean, I've read the file,
他们掌握了谋杀案件的充分证据
and they do have a pretty solid murder case.
- 谋杀案件? - 是的 一位联邦探员
- Murder? - Yeah. Of a federal agent.
不可能 我... 我没有杀任何人
No way. I... I didn't kill anybody.
他们知道了海军秘书官身上的笔有蹊跷
They know about the pen on the Secretary of the Navy.
知道了你出现在餐馆
They know that you were at the restaurant,
知道了一千万美元的事情
and they know about the $10 million.
不过你还能自救
You can help yourself, though.
如果你承认谋杀
If you cop to the murder,
- 可能能减刑 - 我没有杀任何人!
- might reduce sentencing. - I didn't kill anybody!
你对一名联邦探员胸部开了三枪!
You shot a federal agent three times in the chest!
冷静一下
Hey! Take it down a peg.
他说他没有杀任何人 好吗?
He said he didn't kill anybody, okay?
- 先听他怎么说 - 然后你行动迅速
- Let's hear him out. - Then you make it fast.
我没有勒索政府
I did not extort the government,
也没有杀这个探员
and I did not kill this agent.
但是我知道是谁干的
But I know who did.
- 名字 - 爱德华・格瑞斯
- Name. - Edward Gracy.
他以前向我卖过情报
He's sold me info before.
公司的技术机密
Corporate stuff at tech secrets.
这是他第一次提供政府情报
This is the first time he's offered government intel.
这么说你承认了叛国罪
So you're admitting to treason.
我们应该相信吗?
We supposed to believe this?
我不知道是否应该信他
I don't know if I believe him at all.
需要一个地址来证明
Need an address to prove it.
给你
Here you go.
那我的好处呢?
Hey, what about my deal?
你应该和你的律师谈谈
Oh, you'll have to take that up with your lawyer.
你说你是我的律师
You said you were my lawyer.
我没有说 给你我的名片了
No, I didn't. Gave you my card.
这在法庭上能用吗?
Is that gonna hold up in court?
不知道 我也不是律师
I don't know. I'm not a lawyer, either.
好的 得到市中心一家办公室的确认
All right, got confirmation on a downtown office,
以爱德华・格瑞斯的名字登记租用
rent in the name Edward Gracy.
我通知了交警 他们已经待命
I alerted Metro PD, and they're on standby.
已经适应了你的节奏了
Getting used to your pace here.
那你需要穿上这个
Well, then you're gonna need this.
这... 这是旧的吗?
Uh... h-has this been used?
毕晓普
Bishop.
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
当然
Of course.
是...是的
Y... Yes.
是的 马上就到
Yes, right away.
- 怎么了? - 交警那边有问题吗?
- What's the matter? - There a problem with Metro?
不 是国家安全局的上司
No. Uh, it was my boss at NSA.
他们让我立刻回总部报告
They need me back at HQ to debrief immediately.
该出发了
Got to go.
联邦探员!
Federal agents!
爱德华・格瑞斯!
Edward Gracy!
没有人在家
Nobody's home.
你怎么想? 咱们又被耍了吗?
What do you think? We being played again?
检查一下桌子
Check the desk.
只有垃圾邮件
Nothing here but junk mail,
全球通的过期刊物
back issues of GSM.
收件人都是爱德华・格瑞斯
They're all addressed here to Edward Gracy.
这是我们的国际象棋大师
This is our master chess player?
老大 我在这里有发现
Boss, I got something back here.
这绝对是格瑞斯制作窃听器的地方
Well, this is definitely where Gracy makes his bugs,
很明显他还关注心脏病
and apparently raises awareness about heart disease, as well.
慈善邮递员?
Charity mailers?
- 我们的杀手有良知? - 不
- Our killer has a conscience? - Nope.
他的目标有
His targets do.
这里有一张寄给萨拉・波特的海运邮寄单回执
Shipping receipt for a mailer sent to Sarah Porter.
美国海军秘书官 他将窃听器
SECNAV. He's sending the bugs
他在宣传小册子里附赠了窃听器
with the brochures.
就像垃圾邮件里赠的免费礼物一样
Junk mail free gifts.
你没有收到回信地址的标签
Instead of return-address labels,
反而意外收到了一只超级间谍笔
you get a super spy pen?
这么做风险大 又没有保障
It's a big risk with no guarantee.
一不小心就当废品扔掉了
It's gonna make it past your junk drawer,
哪里能逃得过多重威胁预警中心的法眼呢?
let alone MTAC.
他的收据真多
This is full of receipts.
好像他一天二十四小时不停地发邮件
He sends them out like clockwork.
收据都是从同一邮局开出的
These are all from the same post office.
喂?
Hello.
你来这里做什么?
What the hell are you doing here?
这个...
Uh...
好吧 请听我解释
Okay, I can explain.
我一直在找和爱德华・格瑞斯
I kept digging into the name
这个名字有关的信息
Edward Gracy.
我觉得自己... 简直欲罢不能了
I just... I couldn't help myself.
给我回车里去
Get back in your car.
好的 听我说 格瑞斯这个姓氏是一个化名
Okay, but wait. Th-The name Gracy is an alias,
还有 我发现有个信用卡账户每周都会...
and I found an open credit card with weekly purchases...
毕晓普!
Bishop!
...来这间邮局买东西 知道吗?
...a-at this post office, okay?
我... 来这里
I... I came here
是想找找线索
to follow up.
格瑞斯的邮筒就在这间店里
Gracy's P.O. box is inside the store.
这我知道! 关键是他本人也在里面
I know! So is he.
这话我一直想说来着
It's what I'm trying to tell you.
哦
Oh.
看来你一直跟着他
You're on a stakeout.
- 老大? - 毕晓普!
- Boss? - Bishop!
快去!
Go!
不是吧 擒拿罪犯这你也行啊?
What, did you read a book on disarming bad guys?
跟我的三个哥哥学的 你别动!
Three older brothers. Quit squirming!
这把枪应该
I think we'll find this weapon's
和杀了弗莱林的那只相符
a match to the one that killed Flynn.
交给我吧
I'll take it from here.
- 你可以吗? - 当然
- You got it? - Yeah.
好的
All right.
我们走吧 大块头
Here we go, big guy.
怎么了?
What?
我们都是正确的
We were both right.
还把他抓到了
And we got him.
看来你还没有明白 毕晓普
You're still missing the point, Bishop.
找到指纹的匹配对象了
Got a hit on the fingerprint.
他的真名叫赛迪斯・诺克斯
Real name is Thaddeus Knox.
因其在企业做间谍 多次被捕
Multiple arrests for corporate espionage.
他现在又多了叛国和杀人两项罪名了
Now we can add treason and murder.
这完全没道理啊
It doesn't make any sense.
又怎么啦 大明星?
What now, Russell Crowe?
还嫌你今天
Hasn't your beautiful mind
惹得麻烦不够多吗?
gotten you in enough trouble today?
听着 我不查明真相决不罢休 我发现这个
Look, I don't quit until I get it right, and our corporate
小子和整件事毫无关联
pretty boy just doesn't fit into the big picture.
国家安全局和海军罪案调查处
We've never seen him
都没有他的记录
NSA or NCIS.
- 看来他是新手 - 没错
- He's a first-timer. - Exactly.
如果他只想通过给技术员工发窃听器
But if he sends bugs to tech employees
来获取企业机密的话
looking for corporate secrets,
为何要找上海军秘书官呢?
why make the jump to SECNAV
这是犯罪行为 会让他终身监禁的
and a crime that carries out a life sentence?
他大打出手肯定有原因
Something made him leave his comfort zone.
这和观念以及权力都没有关系 而是...
It's not about ideology or power, it's...
而是他想挑战自己
it's about challenging himself,
证明自己的能力
proving that he can do the job.
他想引起谁的注意呢?
Who's he trying to impress?
他的上司
His boss.
好啦 好啦 找到啦
Yup, yup, yup, yup.
难道这些成堆的收据上面有我们想要的答案?
Don't tell me those crazy papers are finally paying off.
- 毕晓普... - 我今早拿到了
- Bishop... - I have staff lists
多重威胁预警中心下属企业的员工名单
from the corporations in MTAC this morning.
除了一家企业 其他所有企业的每个员工
Bugs have been sent to employees of every company
都收到了窃听器
except one.
这家企业就是格瑞斯所在的...
The same company that's paying Gracy.
贝灵哲海运
Beringer Marine.
他们和海军秘书官有什么过节吗?
What do they have against SECNAV?
吉布斯探员
Agent Gibbs.
你来拿更新资料的吗?
You here for the update?
出什么事了吗?
What's going on?
要是我知道就好了
Hell if I know.
秘书官女士让我别管她的事情
Madam Secretary's cut me out of the loop.
是的 我也注意到了
Yeah. I couldn't help but notice
你们俩之前关系挺紧张的
the tension between you two earlier.
我并不介意听命于人
You know, I don't mind taking orders.
但是我希望命令来自于海军人员
I'd prefer they come from fellow Marines,
或者是曾经当过海军的人
or someone who's served.
我明白
I hear you.
让一个平民去下令 并让成千上万的
A civilian giving orders that affects thousands
军事人员服从于他 对于这种事情我最愤怒了
of military personnel pisses me off more than you know.
几个月前
Few months back,
我被提名为海军秘书官候选人之一
I was on the short list for the SECNAV appointment.
我觉得很光荣 但是我没有接受这个重担
I was honored, but didn't feel right about it.
为什么呢?
Why?
- 你挺合适的 - 也许吧
- You seem qualified. - Maybe.
但是我没有参过军
But I haven't served in uniform.
而我是十分尊重军人的
And I have too much respect for those who have.
比如说你
Like you.
波特自以为
It's not right
什么都懂 但是事实并非如此
for Porter to pretend she knows what they need.
她应该像我一样 做出正确的选择
She should've done the right thing, like I did,
拒绝参选海军秘书官一职的
and declined the position.
但是...
But...
她现在不得不拒绝此项殊荣了
I guess she'll have to now.
这是什么?
What is this?
国家安全局的窃听器
A bug at the NSA.
真是意想不到啊
Who would've thought?
你背叛了我 长官?
You turn on me, Marine?
这里唯一的叛徒就是你 沃德
The only turncoat here is you, Ward.
你雇了企业间谍让我在众人面前
By hiring one of your corporate spies
下不了台 你还让整个国家陷于危险之中
to embarrass me, you put the entire country at risk.
我和你说的事情毫无关系
I had nothing to do with that.
我只想保护我的国家
I only want to protect this country
以及捍卫国家安全的人
and the people defending it.
我没有参过军 但是我懂得责任
I may not have served, but I know about duty
与牺牲的重要性
and sacrifice.
不是穿上制服就能组个队的
Takes more than a uniform to make a team.
吉布斯探员?
Agent Gibbs?
托尼和麦基告诉我你在这里
Tony and McGee said you'd still be here.
是的
I am.
这么晚了还打搅你... 我很抱歉
Sorry to... bother you so late.
永远别说道歉
Never say you're sorry.
这只能说明你的软弱
It is a sign of weakness.
今天发生了那件事情之后
I thought that was the point.
我以为这就是你想听的
Especially after today.
但是我觉得我最终还是想清楚了
But I think I've finally figured something out.
你真是个寻根究底的人啊 毕晓普?
You always got to have the right answer, don't you, Bishop?
是的
Unfortunately.
如果你愿意听我说完
But if you'll let me finish,
我可以解释为什么我的想法错了
I can explain why that's wrong.
我工作很努力
I work hard.
哪里跌倒 就在哪里爬起
And when I fall, I get right back up.
我很聪明 我希望自己能出一份力
I'm smart, a-and I want to make a difference.
这我可以做得到
And I can.
我太执着于... 做自己了
Been so busy looking at the... the chessboard on my own,
却遗忘了整个团队
I... I forgot to be a part of it.
我之前并不懂得团队合作
I wasn't a team player.
嗯...
So...
我想说的... 就是这些了
that... that's... that's what I wanted to say.
没有其他了
That's it.
嗯 晚安
Um, good night.
还是说... 祝你好运吧
Or good... good luck.
算了吧
Never mind.
你有东西忘了拿
You forgot something.
哦 那不是我的
Uh, that's not mine.
上面写着你的名字
It's got your name on it.
这是我几年之前给海军罪案调查处
This is my NCIS application
发的个人简历
from years ago.
后来我去国家安全局工作了
Before I took the job at NSA.
这件事情你怎么知道的?
How did you know about this?
你的名字听着很熟悉 我回去查了查
Your name sounded familiar; I went back and looked it up.
所以你今天才带我去查案?
That's why you brought me along today.
看来你也是不喜欢合作的人
You play chess, too.
我只想看看你是否还愿意接受挑战
I wanted to see if you were still up for a challenge.
为什么?
Why?
我想把你留下来
I'd like to keep you around.
学习学习共同责任
Joint duty assignment.
什么?
What?